Guide to the Paul Davidoff papers, 1951-1985
Davidoff, Paul papers, 1951-1985
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Paul Davidoff Papers, 1951-1985
4250
Paul Davidoff, 1930-1984.
26.1 cubic ft.
Student papers, files, correspondence, campaign materials, reports, studies, clippings, articles, books, legal papers, and course outlines.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers relating to Paul Davidoff's career as a city planner, including his civil rights activism on housing discrimination.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Paul Davidoff graduated from Allegheny College in 1952, attended Yale Law School, graduated from the University of Pennsylvania's School of Planning and Architecture in 1956, and received a law degree from Pennsylvania in 1961. He served as a planner for the Delaware County Planning Commission, the New Canaan Planning Commission, Voorhees, Walker, Smith & Smith, and the New York City Planning Commission. From 1958 to 1965, he taught in the City Planning Dept. of the University of Pennsylvania. He served as professor and director of the graduate program of the Urban Planning Program at Hunter College from 1965 to 1969. He was the Democratic candidate for the U.S. Congress from the 26th Congressional District, New York in 1968. In 1969, with Neil Gold, he formed and became Executive Director of the Suburban Action Institute, which became the Metropolitan Action Institute in 1980. His work with both organizations included supervision of research projects, zoning litigation, corporate relocation studies, other expert testimony, conference and fundraising activities, teaching and lecturing at a number of institutions, consulting, and publishing. In 1982, Davidoff and the Metropolitan Action Institute became associated with Queens College. Paul Davidoff died in December 1984.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes student papers; files documenting his early work as a city planner; lecture notes, correspondence, and subject files from the University of Pennsylvania and Hunter College; campaign materials from the 1968 election; and alphabetical subject files and project files of correspondence, reports, studies, clippings, and publications of the Suburban Action Institute and the Metropolitan Action Institute. Subjects include equality in access to suburban housing, exclusionary zoning policies and laws, creation of non-profit mechanisms for building mixed-income housing in suburban communities, discriminatory federal funding suits in Hartford, Conn. and elsewhere; discriminatory zoning cases including Madison and Mahwah, N.J., and Brookhaven, N.Y.; the role of large corporations in abetting discriminatory practices, including action against RCA; the creation of accessory apartments in single-family housing units; inclusionary revitalization; a study of the civil rights impact of Westway; and projects in Port Arthur, Texas, Hoboken, N.J., the lower east side of New York City, Smith Haven Mall in Yonkers, and Starrett City in Brooklyn.
Also includes correspondence, reports, and legal papers pertain to a landmark suit against the Philadelphia suburb of Mount Laurel, N.J. Also, books published by Suburban Action and Metropolitan Action as well as articles by and about Paul Davidoff and his wife Linda, also a city planner.
Also publications and offprints of Paul Davidoff and a selection of Davidoff's course outlines for teaching urban planning.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Davidoff, Paul, 1930-1984.; Davidoff, Linda.; University of Pennsylvania. Dept. of City Planning.; Queen's College (New York, N.Y.) Metropolitan Action Institute.; Suburban Action Institute.
Subjects:
City planning--New York (State); City planning--New Jersey.; Community development, Urban.; Housing.; Land subdivision.; Suburbs.; Urban policy.; Zoning law.; City planning and redevelopment law.; Suburban life.; Discrimination in housing.
Places:
New York Suburban Area.; Mount Laurel (N.J.); Mahwah (N.J.); Hoboken (N.J.); Yonkers (N.Y.); Porter Arthur (Tex.); Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); New York (N.Y.)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Student papers
Box 1
Series II. Alphabetical files, 1956-1969
Box 1-4
Series III. Suburban Action Institute, alphabetical files
Box 5-11
Series IV. Alphabetical files, 1970-1979
Box 12-13
Series V. Alphabetical files, 1980-1984
Box 13-14
Series VI. Metropolitan Action Institute, general files
Box 14
Series VII. Metropolitan Action Institute, alphabetical files
Box 15-16
Series VIII. Correspondence
Box 17
Series IX. Project files
Box 18-24
Series X. Articles, publications, etc.
Box 25
Series XI. Clippings from scrapbooks
Box 26
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Student papers
  - Allegheny College- student papers (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Yale Moot Court of Appeals, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Conservation of municipal expenditures (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Open Space Ratio- 43 districts- NYC zoning (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Powelton Study (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Powelton Study and papers for Wheaton (nonacquisitional rehab) and Meyerson - Theory (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Questionnaires (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Slum Clearance: A Public Abuse" Charles Abram's Housing Seminar (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Student reports and exams, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - PD - student planning papers (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Student work (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Westport Traffic Section- 2nd and 3rd copies of original draft (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Wheaton Rehabilitation Costs - dif. Methods (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Zoning NYC (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Zoning: New York City (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Zoning revisited (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Series II. Alphabetical files, 1956-1969
  - Abramson, Paul (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - PD-ACSP Speech, April 1966 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - ADA (Americans for Democratic Action) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - ADA testimony, July 27, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - ADA (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Davidoff- ADA Housing Program, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - ADA - New York (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - ADA - Senate testimony, July 1967 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - AIP Journal- articles for review (American Institute of Planners (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - AIP Journal (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - AIP (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - AIP Washington Conference - 50th Anniversary, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Advocacy and pluralism (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Advocacy article "AIP Proceedings" (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Advocacy (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Advocacy book/article (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Advocacy Planning Conference (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - PD - Newark AIP Speech (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - PD paper: AIP Convention, August 1964 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - ARCH (Architects' Renewal Committee in Harlem) (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - ASPO (American Society of Planning Officials) (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Davidoff AIP Address, Newark, August 1964 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - ASPO PD - Ghetto speech (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - ASPO Speech Regarding Ghetto, April 1967 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Speech- A Rebuilt Ghetto Does Not a Model City Make- Texas, April 1967 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - PD - Chapter for ASPO (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - ASPO Chapter (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Battery Park (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Bacon Speech: Davidoff (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Berger, Wallace (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Campaign (Congress) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Blacks (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Gass, Peter (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Italians (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Leaflet #1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Minutes - Campaign Committee (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Miscellany (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Mount Vernon (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - NCEC (National Committee for an Effective Congress) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Ostrow, Robert (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Press (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Youth (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Zoning Ad (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Chester/Crozier Speech, February 11, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Davidoff- CCCP, February 4, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - CC PEP (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Civil Rights (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - PD- College Management Review, September 1966 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Columbus (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Columbus (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Community Relations Service (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - PD-Cornell Speech (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Davidoff - Critiques of Choice Theory (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - PD - C.U.E. Study (Ed Parks) (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Curriculum, Summer 1965 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Davidoff - Rafsky Slayton Debate, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Davidoff and Reiner (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - PD - articles (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Davidoff, Paul L. press clips (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - PD - press clips (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Davidoff - press clips (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - PD - WBAI Broadcasts (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - PD v. Don Elliott (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - PD speeches - Misc. (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - PD speeches - Misc. (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Farbman (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Gans, Herbert J. (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Clippings on Ghetto (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Goal v. Programs - ADA - Phillips (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Justin Gray (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Greenwich zoning (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Guaranteed income (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - David Gurin (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Hartman, Chester (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - H.E.W. (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Housing Association - policy (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Housing - Goals for NYC, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - HUD (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Hunter College (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - JAIP - Response to Glazer, November 1964 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - JAIP Article, November 1965 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Job offers (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Kennedy, Robert (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - King, Dr. Martin Luther (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Land Study- Moskof - Pres. Committee on Urban Housing (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Larchmont- PD (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Law course (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Lincoln Square zoning (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Mamaroneck Schools (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Mamaroneck (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Manhattan 2000 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript review (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - McCarthy- urban programs (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Miscellany (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
  - MIT Poverty Conference, May 8, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - MIT Conference "Inventing the Future", October 1966 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - MIT Conference, October 1966 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Metropolitan Development Conference For Equal Opportunity (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Mobilization FY - PD memos (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Mobilization FY - Housing (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Mount Vernon Model Cities (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Mumford (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - NAACP Paper, October 21, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - NCDH (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - New Canaan, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 18-19)
  - Newman, Dorothy (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Newark (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - N.Y. CRP (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - New York State Housing Program (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - N.Y.C. Master Plan- goal formulation (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - New York Times Guest Editorial (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - New York Times 800 words draft (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - NIMH Grant Application (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - PD - Letters to the Times (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Norwalk CORE v. Norwalk Redevelopment Agency (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - John Page (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Peattie, Lisa (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Perspecta article, October 1966 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Phila. Public Schools- Integration, etc. (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Philadelphia Housing Association Study- policy, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Piven and Cloward (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - PEO (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Planners for Equal Opportunity (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Priorities/County (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Reiner (Tom Reiner) (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Reiner, Janet (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Ropert Brewery (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Reader in Planning Law (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Reich, Charles (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Reich, Charles (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Social Planning Curriculum (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Social Planning (sociology approach) (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Social Policy (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Stamford zoning (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Stryker's Bay (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Suburbs (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Sutton, Percy (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Speech to Temple Administrators, October 1966 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Thabit, Walter (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Theory of Planning- general (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - U.D.A., Washington, October 7-8, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - U.D.A. papers (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - U.D.A. speech (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights- Parks (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights- Educational Park Report (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Paper for Civil Rights Comm, Fall 1966 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - U.S. Civil Rights Report - Educational Park (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - University of Pennsylvania - Law, Spring 1959 (Box 4, Folder 15-16)
  - University of Pennsylvania - Lay and social planning, Spring 1965 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - University of Pennsylvania - theory, Spring 1961 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - University of Pennsylvania - theory, Fall 1961 (Box 4, Folder 19-20)
  - University of Pennsylvania - theory notes, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - University of Pennsylvania - Department of City and Regional Planning, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - University of Pennsylvania- Department of City and Regional Planning, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Teaching materials- program outlines (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Urban Coalition (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Urban Land Study (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Venezuela / Caracus (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Wade, John (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Waterside Housing Project (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Webber, Melvin (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Wm. L.C. Wheaton (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - White House pickets (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - N. Williams (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - World Trade Center (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Xmas (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Yale Moot Court of Appeals (Box 4, Folder 36-37)
  - Yale L.R. article (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Yale Rabin (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Zwirner v. Greenbery, Fall 1964 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Zoning - general (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Zoning - Dallas- special permits (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Series III. Suburban Action Institute, alphabetical files
  - Advocacy Planning - San Diego Paper, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Vice President Agnew (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - A.I.P. (American Institute of Planners) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Arlington Heights (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Berenson (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Bergen County case (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Bergen County, New Jersey (Box 5, Folder 7-8)
  - Bloomfield Coventry, Fall 1978 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Briefs (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Bristol Zoning and Institutions (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Brookhaven- counter plan (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Governor Cahill (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Candlewood Lake (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Cases: Davenport, Iowa (NCDH) (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Cases: Rodriguez, Demetrio P., et al. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - City edges (Box 5, Folder 17-20)
  - City of Parma, Ohio (Box 5, Folder 21-23)
  - Conferences, 1969 +++ (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Congress, U.S. (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Davidoff, Jerry (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Davidoff, Linda and Paul. Commentary (AIP Journal), January 1974 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Davidoff, Linda and Paul, and Neil N. Gold: Suburbs Have To Open Their Gates (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Davidoff, Paul, "Esthetics, Equity, and Economics." (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Davidoff, Paul, "The Song of the Suburbs Is Over There", December 1973 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Review/suburbs books, Aug. 1976 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Davidoff, Paul - personal (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Davidoff, Paul resume (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Hills, Secretary of HUD v. Gautreaux et al., January-April 1976 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Housing and Urban Development Legislation (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Photographs: Paul Davidoff and others (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - H and CD/ applications (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Jobs/Effects of Industrial Suburbanization on Central City Employees: Breitbart, Myrna (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Labor Department Research Proposal (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Embry Application (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Housing segregation (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Government contracts - general HUD (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Hunter Regional Studio (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Income data (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Internal Revenue Service (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Land policy (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Larchmont (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Lewisboro (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Lewisboro News Release, November 13, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Low-Income Housing Coalition (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Madison Township - documents (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Oakwood at Madison Brief (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Madison (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Mahwah Project (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Management education, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Massachusetts Legislation and Other (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Mayer, Albert (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - H. Carl McCall and Assoc. (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Mead, Margaret (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Messinger (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Metropolitan Housing (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Mitchell Field (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Model Zoning Ordinances - Cluster (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Morris County, New Jersey (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Morris County, New Jersey (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Morse, Pat (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Mount Laurel (Box 6, Folder 31-32)
  - Mount Laurel Case Materials (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Mt. Vernon Schools Housing (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Mumford (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Municipal Assistance Corporation (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Municipal Housing Size Suit: Brandt, Haughey, Penberthy, Lewis (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Mussen/Minority Housing References (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - NAACP Legal Defense Fund (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - NAACP (Box 7, Folder 2-3)
  - National Committee Against Discrimination in Housing (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - National Corporation for Housing Partnerships (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - National Endowment for the Arts (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - National Endowment for the Arts - Consultant Papers (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - National Housing Goals - National Report (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - National Conference On Land Policy (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - National Urban Policy Roundtable (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Newark Tenants Union (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - National Land Use Bill (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - New Canaan, Fall 1975 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - NEWCOE (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - New Canaan, Connecticut Exclusionary Zoning In The Suburbs - thesis- Ellen Szita (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - New Canaan Case (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - New Canaan (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - New Castle Case (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - New Castle Decision (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - New Castle (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - New Castle - sewer (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - New Haven Suburban Action (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - New Haven (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - N.J. General (Mt. Laurel Followings) (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Governor Byrnes Executive Order (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - New Jersey Case (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - New Jersey Legislation (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - New Jersey School Decision, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - New Jersey Tax Policy (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - New Jersey Elderly Population (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - N.Y. - NE N.J. // Jobs- BLS Statistics (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - New Jersey Census, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - New Jersey Census, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - New Jersey State Coalition (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - New York - New Jersey Area - Commuting Patterns (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - New Jersey New Multifamily Housing (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - New Jersey Municipal Finances (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - New Jersey - R.P.A (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - New York State Division of Human Rights Hearing (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - New York State Planning Enab. Revision (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - New York State - Misc. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - New York Legislation (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - New York State Area File (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - N.Y. Times (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - New York Council on the Humanities (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - New Stanton (Box 8, Folder 13-14)
  - New Towns (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - New Town Racial and Economic Integration Proposal to Foundation- Jack Brizius (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Non-Profit Housing Center (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Northboro, Massachusetts (Buckle) (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - North Hempstead, New York (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - North Hills, New York (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - N.E. Governors Conference (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Northwestern University Center for Urban Affairs (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Norwalk Zoning (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - OEO -Project on Land Use Controls (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Office Space Study (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Open Space (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Operation Breakthrough (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Organizing (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - PATH (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Pennsylvania - File Copies (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - General- PA (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Pennsylvania Decisions (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Pennsylvania (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - State of Pennsylvania (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Peretz, Martin (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Periscope (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Perlman, Janice (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Norman Perlstein Proposal (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Ron Perry- Jobs and Workers (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Petaluma (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Ben Peterson (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Thomas Pettigrew (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Philadelphia (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Piscataway Township (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Planning for People Coalition (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Planning Legislation (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Play Conference (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Robert L. Popper (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Population Data (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Potomac Institute Zoning Conferences (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Property Value Insurance (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Press Release (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Sisters of Providence (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Public Relations (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Puerto Rico (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Rainwater, Lee (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Ramapo, New Jersey (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - "Can the Town of Ramapo Pass A Law to Bind The Rights of the Whole World?" Fred Bosselman (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Revenue-Sharing Litigation (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Revenue-Sharing (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Randolph Township, New Jersey (Box 9, Folder 27-28)
  - Ray, Denison (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Ravitch, Richard (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Real Estate and Land Offerings (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - RCA (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Relocation of Fed - Facilities (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Remedies (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Rent Supplement Case (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Reorganization Bills, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Report of Federal Housing Program (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Requests for New York State Housing Program (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Ribicoff, Speech (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Ridgefield (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Rosenstiel, Lewis (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - SAI - Formation of SAI and GCDC (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - SAI - General Purposes (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - SAI - Goals and Objectives (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - SAI - Income, August 1972-June 1973 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - SAI - Income Projection, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - SAI - Newsletter (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - SAI - Planning Department (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - SAI - Public Relations, Press and Publicity (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - SAI - Research Department (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - SAI - Student Employment (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - SAI - Summary of Litigation (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - SAI - Technical Assistance (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - SAI - Thank You (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - SAI - NYS Attorney General (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - SAI - Tax Status- Material Furnished IRS (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - SAI - Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - SAI - Employment - General (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - SAI - Fiscal (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - SAI - Staff Resumes (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - SAI - Program Proposal (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - SAI - Davidoff, Paul clippings and resumes (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - SAI - Davidoff, Linda: Misc. (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - SAI - Current Department Operations (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - SAI - Board of Directors (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - SAI - General (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - SAI - Trust Agreement (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - SAI - Board of Trustees (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - SAI - Budget, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - SAI - Statement of Purpose (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - SAI - Annual Report, 1976-1977 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - SAI - Annual Report Draft (Box 10, Folder 31)